# **Bruce A. Lee**

Email: brucelee352@gmail.com · Phone: (407) 486-4784

Portfolio: brucelee352.github.io

# **Objective:**

Hello, I'm Bruce. I have 3 years' experience in cloud & data pipeline management in startup & education contexts, using PostgreSQL, R, Python. I'm a Data Engineer looking for my next opportunity to engineer sustainable pipelines within the cloud.

### **Skills:**

SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Python, R, Tableau, Salesforce, Google BigQuery, Git, GCP

# **Experience:**

Freelance 10/2022 — Present

Data Engineering Consultant:

- Establishes relationships with in-network stakeholders to assist in the workshop of vertically integrated data ingestion
  pipelines for enterprise use.
- Develops SQL queries and Python code for data transformation and aggregation, resulting in a 30% reduction in processing time for reporting and dashboards via transformation pipeline.
- Automates data pipeline workflows using Python and BigQuery leading to a more streamlined and error-free reporting process for clients, capturing the appropriate messaging for their needs via Tableau dashboards.

Branching Minds 7/2021 — 10/2022

Analytics Engineer:

- Branching Minds is an Ed-Tech startup that improves data flow and intervention outcomes for school districts.
- Developed and maintained ETL pipelines for student, teacher, and assessment data across 40+ districts & their 3rd party vendors using R as the transformation layer, AWS Athena, and PostgreSQL.
- Made both routine and ad-hoc reporting for school district and internal staff via the org's proprietary PostgreSQL database and AWS Athena Data Lake and automated data imports from 3rd party vendor APIs.
- Utilized AWS Athena to manage, query, and analyze large datasets, optimizing data retrieval processes and ensuring efficient data storage for the organization.
- Orchestrated data pipelining via AWS Step Functions to streamline the ETL process for the organization.

Vocabulary.com 8/2019 —5/2021

Customer Success Manager:

- Championed customer success through initiative-taking engagement and personalized solutions, utilizing NPS Surveys,
   Salesforce for customer management and Zendesk for efficient ticket resolution to help mitigate churn.
- Leveraged data analytics via Salesforce and Tableau integration to capture the voice of the customer.
- Created KPIs that highlighted improvements in client satisfaction and product enhancement.
- Sustained a 98% satisfaction rating across the East Coast and international markets—expertly conveyed technical solutions and troubleshooting to a diverse customer base.

AMI Kids Inc. 8/2018 — 6/2019

Vocational Data Analyst:

- Oversaw data analysis and delivered KPIs via Excel for a federally funded program, managing 3,000+ participants.
- Assisted in compiling data for compliance reporting to the DOE, DJJ and DOL to ensure continued funding.
- Provided insights across 21 Southeastern U.S. sites using Excel as the primary tool for strategic fund allocation.

#### **Education:**

University of Central Florida

· Sociology, BA